MADELINE OHAUS

EXHIBITS AND LOANS
REGISTRATION ASSISTANT

CONTACT INFORMATION

Phone: 704-807-3883

Email: Madeline.ohaus@colorado.edu LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/madeline-

ohaus/

Twitter: @MadelineOhaus Website: madelineohaus.com

SUMMARY

I am an emerging museum professional specializing in collections, registration, curation, and education. I recently completed my Master's of Arts in Anthropology with a concentration in Museum and Heritage Studies at the University of Denver. My thesis focused on LGBTQ+ representation within museum collections and exhibits. I currently work part-time as a Registration Assistant at the Denver Art Museum. In this role, I work closely with the Traveling Exhibits and Loan Registrars to ensure objects are correctly cataloged and ready for display or travel. In my career, I strive to make museum collections and exhibitions inclusive and accessible for underrepresented populations.

EDUCATION

University of Denver

Anthropology MA Concentration in Museum and Heritage Studies GPA: 4.0

University of Colorado Boulder

Anthropology BA Concentration in Archaeology

RELEVANT SKILLS

- ·Artifact Handling and Interpretation
- ·Argus Database
- ·ArchiveSpace + Alma
- ·Museum Registration Methods
- Cataloging + Archival Processing
- ·Artifact Research
- ·Historical Research
- ·Condition Reporting
- ·Community Outreach
- ·Education and Facilitation
- ·Curriculum Development
- ·Customer Service

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Registration Assistant

Denver Art Museum, July 2022 - Present

- •Assist with coordinating art shipments, including packing and arrangements, insurance coverage, and associated documentation
- ·Unpack, pack, catalog, condition, and move artwork
- •Physically number, generate tags and barcode IDs, and rehouse incoming artworks
- •Prepare registration documentation (receipts, condition reports, loan agreements, etc.)
- ·Undertake data entry and reporting on Argus collections database
- •Maintain object files and records and work on collections research and cataloging projects
- •Execute condition documentation photography in digitized formats
- ·Assist with collection inventories and storage moves
- •Oversee access to and appointments in the Registrar's artwork-holding area
- •Assist with file and records room projects, including archival file organization, rehousing, and clean up
- •Schedule and oversee courier appointments both in person and virtually

Archival Processing Assistant

The Dance Archive, August 2021 - July 2022

- •Executed cataloging and archival processing (arrangement, description, preservation, and re-housing) for collections in multiple formats •Sorted, shelved, retrieved, and maintained rare and/or specifically collected books/publications and non-circulating materials housed in Special Collections
- •Developed descriptive metadata for archival materials, and searched for these materials to meet processing, reference, and institutional needs
- •Created and updated digital records for collections within ArchivesSpace
- ·Identified materials in need of repair and conservation
- •Transcribed oral histories for the Living Legends of Dance series
- ·Conducted inventory and relabeling projects

Curatorial Services and Collections Access Intern

History Colorado Center, October 2020 - August 2021

- •Interned two days a week with Curatorial Services & Collections Access •Solicited, processed, and cataloged donations to build the LGBTQ+
- ·Conducted, indexed, and researched oral histories relating to Colorado's LGBTQ+ history
- ·Curated a registration window exhibit on LGBTQ+ history
- ·Inventoried artifacts and updated catalog records to be deaccessioned
- •Utilized Argus software to update and create new records for artifacts within the collection
- •Scanned and digitized accession ledgers from the 1900s to make them accessible for crowdsourcing projects

Guest Services Agent

collections

History Colorado Center, August 2020 - August 2021

- •Responded to inquiries regarding scheduling museum visits, group tours, programs, and lectures
- ·Organized, tracked, and prepared membership materials
- •Provided troubleshooting and maintenance on museum audio-visual technologies, including televisions, projectors, and computers
- ·Trained, managed, and worked alongside volunteers at the front desk and host positions
- •Served as a representative of the museum, utilizing professional and academic knowledge of collections, exhibits, and state history to address guest questions
- •Oversaw on-exhibit artifacts, ensuring an ideal environment for collections by thorough attention to detail and reporting on conditions and conservation needs
- $\cdot \textsc{Executed}$ admission and gift store sales through the point-of-sale system
- ·Assisted in building and preparing exhibit spaces and aided with the installation and de-installation of artifacts

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY CONTINUED

After School Program Lead

History Colorado Center, August 2019 - August 2020

- •Facilitated after school enrichment program
- •Recruited and registered students
- •Collaborated with other staff members to plan lessons
- •Created a space of belonging so students from varied social, cultural, ethnic, and economic backgrounds were represented and had a voice in the activities
- •Ensured program met standards, that all materials were prepared for each day's program, and safety regulations were being followed
- ·Assisted with the evaluation of the program
- •Was an ambassador for History Colorado outside the museum walls and served as a positive role model for students

Cultural Resources Field Technician

SWCA Environmental Consultants, March 2019 - July 2019

- ·Conducted pedestrian and shovel test surveys
- ·Worked 10-12 hour days six days a week in the field, carrying heavy equipment and hiking long distances
- ·Identified both prehistoric and historical artifacts on the surface and within excavated soil
- ·Worked with TerraSync application on Trimble unit
- •Completed comprehensive reports on daily work, including shovel test and artifact descriptions, geographical and environmental logs, and photographic records
- ·Worked with landowners to communicate the purpose of the work and engage their cooperation
- ·Washed and prepared artifacts for lab analysis

Youth Enrichment Specialist

Boys and Girls Club of Metro Denver, October 2018 - March 2019

- •Planned and facilitated enrichment classes for students
- •Planned and led afterschool activities with a focus on character, leadership, academics, and healthy lifestyles
- ·Maintained collaborative partnerships with the school leaders, key stakeholders, and program partners
- Organized and executed community events such as dinners, volunteer events, family nights, and field trips
- ·Assisted in the purchasing of materials and supplies, maintaining budgets and inventory

Teen Science Scholar Program Assistant

Denver Museum of Nature and Science, June 2018 - August 2018

- •Supported interns involved in the program in any capacity necessary, both on-site and off-site
- •Participated in chaperoning multiple full-day field trips
- •Ensured basic care and provided academic, social, and emotional support to the interns
- ·Led and assisted with programs that engaged participants
- •Worked to educate interns in the field of archaeology at the Magic Mountain site and museum anthropology within DMNS collections
- ·Coordinated intern schedules and associated events
- ·Worked with other departments to make sure operations ran smoothly